#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/zekai-zhang-1578251a2 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Web Design
Product Design
Front-end Design

Certifications

**Designing Innovation to Action** 

# Zekai Zhang

Building products that bring people closer, with Al and passion New York, New York, United States

## Summary

I wrote this intro almost 4 years ago, and the philosophy hadn't changed much - besides I was in school

"At New York University, I'm majoring in Economics, along with minors in Business Studies, Math, and Computer Science. However, my interests extend far beyond the world of numbers and graphs about supply & demand.

I'm deeply passionate about the intersection of arts and technology. I believe that technology can be used as a tool to make people's lives more efficient and equitable, and art is a powerful medium for learning about the world and reflecting on ourselves.

I've always been drawn to startups because they're built on the foundation of disrupting old-fashioned ways with innovation. Specifically, I'm passionate about three types of startups: 1. those that use technology to solve real-world problems and bring joy to people 2. those that make art and visual content more accessible to the public, and 3. those in social networking and media that aim to bring people together online/IRL without any negative intentions.

Before, I founded Qujian, a community-based social platform that connects introverted college students with in-person activities catered to various interests. It encourages people to spend less time online and facilitates exciting meetups with one tap. From day one, I was fascinated by the process of building things from the ground up, and providing true value for the community was the best feeling I ever felt.

When I'm not immersed in the world of startups, I love to explore the arts scene in New York by visiting galleries, capturing exciting moments in life with my old Leica camera, and exploring the city on my electric skateboard. I'm always eager to connect with people who share similar and different ideas. You can find me here or email me at zz2447@nyu.edu. Let's chat!"

# Experience

Gobi

Head of Growth November 2023 - Present (10 months) New York City Metropolitan Area

OutWeGo Product Design and Marketing July 2023 - February 2024 (8 months) San Francisco Bay Area

Stealth Startup
Head of Product and Design
March 2023 - February 2024 (1 year)

- Led the design research, and created wireframes and high-fidelity desktop mockups of the MVP
- Directed the user research and the market research, designed the product's landing page that effectively conveys the value proposition of the product
- Collaborated closely with the design team, providing guidance on UI, graphic designs, and UX design to deliver intuitive user experiences across all projects

My exploration in Web3
Product, Strategy & Community
June 2022 - January 2024 (1 year 8 months)
New York City Metropolitan Area

- · There are wins and losses
- My researches were focused on Social Web, NFTs, RWA applications, and Creator economy
- Team leader in the youngest team in Eth Denver 2023 hackathon
- Creator economy platform received strategic investments from various VCs (I designed it)
- Token Sharing platform grew a community of 10k and 6 figures transactions in USDT within 1 month of launching (I led the community operation)
- Hosted various events in New York and LA (It was fun)

#### Visura

Research and Development Product Manager May 2022 - February 2023 (10 months)

- Conducted research in the NFT photography landscape, with a focus on ownership and long-term viability
- Conducted customer discovery for editors and creators, and created user journey & flow map for UX analysis
- Led the market research in pricing and distribution channels of editorial photos, and recommended pricing strategy

#### 趣见 ToSee

#### Founder

June 2020 - August 2022 (2 years 3 months)

Shanghai, China

- Directed the initial idea validation process through surveys, focus groups, and talking to customers
- Led the research in customer discovery and UX design interviews based on users' needs
- Engaged in daily operations such as hosting 300+ virtual and IRL events for 50+ sub-communities
- Collaborated with existing college social platforms, and 25 local merchants for promotional marketing
- Designed and launched no-code MVP to test out various hypotheses, features, and user preferences on UI designs
- Developed marketing content for WeChat Official Accounts and TikTok with graphic designs and general strategies
- Achieved 60% user retention rate and 35% in-person events engagement rate over two years

#### Tencent

**Product Operations Intern** 

December 2021 - March 2022 (4 months)

Remote

- Researched the Chinese mobile gaming industry with a focus on ACGN games about market environments, regulatory policies, competitive analysis, and studios' product data
- Analyzed 2 ACGN games in detail on game mechanics, rules, components, and past updates
- Collaborated with each game's marketing teams on advertising, analyzing revenue streams and user-engagement rate

T-LAB

T12 Fellow

August 2021 - August 2021 (1 month)

Shanghai, China

A selective crash program which is backed with 60+ funds and venture capitals, helps fellow students get to know about angel investing and early stage investments.

FlashMeet

Founder

September 2019 - June 2020 (10 months)

New York, NY, United States

KuzoClass

KuzoClass Felllow

February 2020 - May 2020 (4 months)

Shanghai Pudong Development Bank

Finance Intern

June 2018 - August 2018 (3 months)

Shanghai, China

- Analyzed back-end credits models and transaction data to evaluate the risk level of 1000 clients
- Assisted marketing team on initial user acquisition for the newly designed credit card
- Assisted the management team in the daily operations in the office

### Education

New York University

Bachelor's degree, Economics · (2019 - 2022)

SMU Cox School of Business

Bachelor's degree (2017 - 2019)